Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Faith comes by hearing.
That is why we need to hear about healing anointing.
That is why we need to hear about blessing anointing.
That is why we need to hear about delivering anointing.
I will take it again.
Faith comes by hearing.
That is why we need to hear about what? - Healing anointing,
deliverance anointing and blessing anointing.
Faith comes by hearing.
We all know Jesus always responds to those who put a demand on Him.
Always.
He always responds to those who put what? - A demand on Him.
What a blessing to teach people who are hungry for the Word!
You know..
When you have people who are hungry for the Word and you are teaching them - what a blessing!
So I believe I'm in the midst of people who are hungry for the Word.
Are you one of them?
I can't hear you.
[Yes!]
Thank you! Hallelujah!
Now the job is half done; you have scored fifty percent.
I say you have scored fifty percent.
If you even decide to leave from here now
and then maintain the one you have received, it is OK.
So let's talk about maintenance.
Hallelujah!! What we have been listening to since morning,
if you can meditate over it, over and over and over...
This is what your enemy does not want you to hear!
You know many times when you are at home and you are listening to Emmanuel TV,
there are a lot of distractions.
So the time you have to pay attention to what you hear now is always difficult for you out there
because there are so many things to attend to.
So I want to say congratulations once again!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah.
Let us pray for the viewers.
We want them to have the right focus
because you know what it means if you are out there, in the midst of confusion, distractions.
Here, you switch off your set.
You don't want to hear anything; you have so much grace.
But over there, our viewers at home, anywhere they are,
we know the situation they are in - so many distractions.
So let us pray for them and ask God to give them the right focus in the midst of all.
Stretch your hand. Let's pray together.
Viewers all over the world, we want to be like Jesus in our heart.
We pray for right focus, in the name of Jesus!
Whatever is disturbing you right now -
our heart is always going up and down, thinking about this and that -
leave it for God!
We pray for right focus, in the name of Jesus!
Right focus, in the name of Jesus!
Begin to receive a hearing heart!
A hearing heart!
Pray Along With Prophet T.B. Joshua - Touch Your Screen By Faith In Jesus' Name
In Jesus Christ's name!
Thank You, Lord!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Faith comes by hearing.
That is why we need to hear about about what? - Healing anointing.
And once you hear it, put a demand on it.
When the healing is going on, put a demand on it. If you are sick, you will be healed.
Blessing anointing - when you hear it being pronounced on a person
and you need blessing, put a demand on that blessing anointing
and you will be blessed!
How do we put a demand?
Get connected; just believe.
If there is actually God in the true processing -
true processing means that it is given to us for free and we shall give it to you for free -
without the exchange of money.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Deliverance cannot take place without God's processing.
Healing cannot take place without God's processing.
Blessing can never...
If somebody says, "I am blessed",
are you sure it is God's blessing, or are you talking of man's blessing?
If it is God's blessing, it must go through God's processing.
There is a process for everything.
Processing is more important than the result itself.
You say you are rich. Okay, a rich man.
How you become rich is bigger than your riches - your result.
Processing is bigger than the result itself.
How you get there is bigger than getting there.
This is the problem with people -
everybody wants to be big and get there by following any processing.
No! The processing will help you to maintain the result.
If the processing is tampered with or if the processing is not God's processing,
you will not be able to maintain that result.
So you say, "Oh yes! You become rich".
What processing takes you to those riches?
It matters because to maintain those riches, you need that processing.
If it is not God's processing and you get there, you cannot maintain the riches.
It will disappoint you at a dear time you need it.
That is why you see people who were very rich and today they are poor.
Very rich. At the time of need, the money is gone.
They say, "Ah! The man is there, he is just..."
It is all about processing.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Healing must go through God's processing.
So processing is greater than results
What matters is processing.
Tell your neighbour: What matters is processing!
I can't hear you.
What matters is processing.
What matters is processing
Again and again!
What matters is processing.
It is processing!
So the manner we process our lives is what is working against us or working for us.
You want to get married?
What is the processing of getting married to that man - is it in line with God?
Or the man is handsome that is why you married that man, or the man has money.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If it is in line with God that you get married,
that processing will stand for any challenges that you may have in that marriage.
What can separate men from the love of God?
Nothing, if the processing is of God.
What can separate me from the marriage?
If that marriage follows God's processing, nothing can separate you.
Nothing that you will hear your husband has done, your wife has done -
you will still ask God, you want to know God's opinion.
No matter what happens to the marriage, you still want to know God's opinion
because God can use any foolish thing to strengthen the marriage.
Your business today - you jump from one business to another because of crises.
When you invest in a business and it is not yet coming, you abandon the business.
You cannot abandon a business because of lust.
You cannot abandon a business because of sickness.
You lost, you have spent money, you run bankrupt.
You can't abandon your business because of those things.
You can only abandon a business when God says, "Quit!"
The same thing in marriage -
you cannot abandon your marriage because of crises.
You cannot abandon your marriage because of challenges.
No matter what happens to this marriage, you cannot abandon your marriage because of that.
Unless God says, "Quit!"
If the processing of your marriage is in line with God, nothing can separate you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Sometimes, God can allow foolish things on our way.
Those foolish things are college, school - you need to go to school of embarrassment,
school of praises, school of persecution, school of progress, school of failure.
Many of you that are here today - if I had not graduated in persecution,
how would I be telling you of persecution?
If I had not graduated in accusation, how could I be telling you about accusation?
If I had not gone through the school of hatred -
I know much about hatred; people hate me so dearly.
If I had not gone through and graduated in that,
how would I be standing here and counsel you about hatred?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is just like that!
Processing - tell your neighbour!
Processing!
Processing is very important!
This is what Paul meant when he said, "What can separate me from the love of God?"
Can death, sickness or disease?
He is talking about processing.
If his love for God is in line with the scriptures...
You say, I am a Christian.
When you become a Christian in line with the scriptures, nothing can separate you.
Listen again.
If your marriage is in line with God, with the scriptures, nothing can separate you from that marriage.
Trouble will come, disappointments will come, failure will come.
No! It will come! It will just come and strengthen the marriage.
Even sickness will come - it will just come. After that sickness, the marriage will be strengthened.
Disappointment will come - they will come and tell you, "We saw your wife in so and so place.
Your wife is going out with this so and so. Oh, this is the phone number!" You even see the phone number.
You still need to ask God's opinion about the matter.
You just need to ask God's opinion about the matter.
If God brings you to a relationship, the same God will quit you.
But if you bring yourself to a relationship, you quit yourself.
How did you come about the marriage?
When you come to the marriage by yourself and not by God, you quit when trouble comes.
But when God brings you to a relationship, no matter what happens,
it is the same God who will quit you when it is time.
If you have not heard from God, no matter what happens, you must go through it.
God's processing is the mind of God.
Now you can say that processing is greater than the result itself.
If you follow the right processing and you are not getting the result,
don't worry!
You are about to get the mother of results.
You know there is what we call the mother of miracle.
You do the right thing, but yet, there is no result.
Don't be disappointed.
If you have done the right thing and you are expecting the result to come,
all you need to do is to be patient
Look at Hannah and Samuel!
You are about to get the mother of results.
Look at your case - sometimes you feel sick as a Christian,
you run to God for prayer.
The more you pray, it seems that the sickness is still there.
You keep praying, the sickness is still there.
It is not that God does not hear you.
God may realise that that sickness will strengthen you better,
it will strengthen your desire for Him better than healing.
He will allow you to go through that sickness
so that He can strengthen your desire and your determination for Him.
When we are sick, we keep seeking His face and fast more.
But the moment we are healed, we relax.
So when God realises that your going through the sickness will strengthen your desire for Him,
better than when you are healed.
Or God may realise that your situation may strengthen your desire, your determination for God,
to move you closer to God.
When you have challenges, troubles,
He will leave you until you are very strong - too strong.
Then you get healed.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He is only concerned about the relationship; it is our relationship that matters.
Many of us are here today for what you have been asking God to do for you.
Your business - you want it to prosper. It is not that God does not hear. God hears.
But God realises that when your business prospers, you are likely not able to sit among your people.
You will allow this wealth to start controlling you, instead of the source of that wealth to control you.
When you have so much money, money will now begin to control you.
I need to go to the meeting,
I need to go to sign a contract,
I need to do this -
instead of the source of that, the One who gave you the money to control you.
OK, look at it.
Where you live today, is what your possession can purchase.
When you live in a village and you have money, you will abandon the village.
You go to the city because money has come.
It is nature, it is natural - that is human being for you.
That if you are living in a village
and later you have a business and money comes, you will abandon the village for the city.
It means that it is the money that is controlling us and not the Giver.
You can be very rich and still remain in that village -
develop the village, give them light, build your house and live among your people.
But today, we abandon our people.
Once the money comes, we go to a better place; we look for our colleagues.
If you are less privileged and you are rich, you move to the privileged people.
It is the money that is controlling us. We go into our stature.
That is it.
Some churches you see arrange for different seats.
When you just enter a place of worship, you can see that this is where big people sit.
This is where privileged people sit.
This is where the less privileged people sit.
Who is privileged before God? Who is less privileged before God?
Who is rich before God? Who is famous before God?
God is concerned about the souls that are saved.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
No matter the situation you are in, you can begin to feel the presence of God
by beginning to have it in your mind that you are not alone
Like I am here now, I am not alone.
So, if I want to say something, you check me.
I would not want to say anything that He would not want to hear.
You have to engage Him to show that you know Him and that He is with you.
You have to be talking when someone is talking to you.
When someone is addressing you, don't remain silent - talk.
So that you can erase whatever that is not pleasant.
And on the phone, when you are receiving a phone call - "Hello!"
You too - when you say that "hello", say another one in the spirit
to arrest any situation, any message you want to hear.
"Hello, how are you?" - "Fine."
"Where are you now?" - "Mmh."
You say your prayer before you respond.
That is to show that you are not alone.
So like you are watching me, you have to be saying your prayer.
This is how you will start.
When you start here, you will continue to do that.
When you start here, you will continue to pray. Like when I am talking to you, you have to say something
Begin to say something.
Don't keep silent - if you are silent, your God will be silent.
If you talk, your God will talk.
If you are silent, we cannot place you.
"Mmh." - "T.B. Joshua, how are you?"
You cannot place me - whether I said fine or not fine.
"Mmh."
For you to place me, I have to talk.
It is still processing; we should cherish processing.
Let me give you a good example of this word 'processing'.
I want to pray for you now, but in my heart - now that I am coming to you - I begin to doubt.
"Will God heal this woman? I don't know."
"And I am a liar. I don't think God will heal this woman."
"Will God heal this woman? I don't think God will heal this woman."
"Be healed! Be healed!"
God cannot heal because the processing is wrong.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The processing is wrong - from here to where you are.
What is going through my heart, what is going through my mind -
it is processing; we call it ingredients.
To make a soup - if you don't have a good processing in putting those ingredients together,
you can't have a wonderful soup.
But when you put those ingredients together - pepper soup or whatever soup you want to make,
a good one - by the time you finish cooking it, people will enjoy the soup.
The same way with prayer, the same way with your life,
the same way with whatever you will become in the future.
Let us once say, processing.
Processing.
I can't hear you.
The processing of your life is what is affecting you today.
The processing - how you started.
At the beginning, in those days, when you said, "If I finish university, I will settle down.
I will get this, I will get that. I will have a wife.
I will have children - a boy and a girl.
It's okay, I will settle down".
But after you have had all this,
what you are looking for, you have not yet got it.
You say, "If I travel to America, I will stay there and work".
Processing.
We should cherish processing more than the result.
Tell your neighbour.
I can't hear you.
We should cherish processing more than the result.
I can't hear you!
The processing we are talking about that is not in line with God is the food of witchcraft.
When you go by a processing that is not in line with God, that is what witchcraft eats.
When you have something which witchcraft would eat, it will come to you and attack you.
They eat unfaithfulness, they eat disobedience, they eat hatred.
They eat pride and you are a very proud person.
Witchcraft will come to you because that is their food.
Lying - you know how to lie. Witchcraft will come to you and afflict you
because the food of witchcraft is lying.
Disobedience, unfaithfulness, pride, self-centeredness - these are the foods of witchcraft.
When you go by that processing to build your life, business or career,
whatever you build in line with all this, you are giving food for witchcraft.
Witchcraft will be part of you.
Let someone say, processing.
Processing.
I can't hear you!
That's all.
Cherish processing more than the result.
Tell your neighbour.
I can't hear you!
Cherish processing more than the result.
That you are in line with God to build your career, business, does not mean you will not be attacked.
But each attack - promotion.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Take note of that.
Because if I don't put that one now, you would just say,
"What this man is saying - I'm in line with God but I'm being attacked".
If you are in line with God, follow God full step, completely
in whatever you are doing - faithfulness, kindness, goodness, self-control and humility -
to build your life, marriage and children.
There will be a big attack.
The bigger your attack, the greater your improvement.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is why today when you learn that - "Ah! Something happened to this man!"
What you will hear from people is, "If it is God's position, if it is God that called him, he will prevail".
When the incident happened in the church here,
the mind of everybody was that if he is called by God,
no Jupiter - the whole world cannot stop him.
But if he is not called by God, the incident will bring him down.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is what Gamaliel, a professor, said. He said, "Leave this man!"
"Leave this man!
If what he is doing is from God, you will not be able to bring him down,
whatever you do to him you are doing it to yourself.
Leave him alone!
But if what he is doing is of man's origin, you will get rid of him".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That you are in line with God, you follow God's steps, step-by-step to build your life,
does not mean attacks and challenges will not come
but when they come, each challenge will take you higher.
Once again - processing.
Cherish processing more than results.
Tell your neighbour.
When you want to achieve something, what you do to achieve it is better than the achievement.
Look at your education today.
You say you are a professor, you are a graduate, you have studied, you face challenges.
If you know what you went through to achieve the position you have achieved,
it is the processing that is working against us.
We get it and leave God behind.
We can read and understand what we are reading but we don't know that
education is not success but it is to help us get success.
There is what we call supernatural gift.
Human natural gift - when you have this human natural gift,
you can come out first class, the best student in the school.
But there is a difference between supernatural and human natural gift.
You can be the most intelligent, the most brilliant student in the world, coming out first class -
human natural.
It is the supernatural that takes us to places with peace of heart.
That is why it is possible in the world today to be the best in your career.
Are you a footballer? The best footballer in the world?
Whatever you are doing -
speaking skills, ability to inspire - you can be the best in the world
and yet not believe in God.
You can do all this without God because all this can be achieved by human natural gift.
How you process your documents will determine the outcome.
Cherish processing more than the result.
Somebody may sit an exam for you, and you may not be the one that sits for it.
Somebody will do it for you and you come out first class.
Processing!
You are not the one that did the exam.
You carry the certificate; somebody has done it for you.
That is wrong processing.
Processing is better, greater than the result.
These are the challenges we are facing today.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You say you are a Christian.
Christianity has a process.
If all this processing is not right, and you say you are a Christian,
you will confess Christianity but you will not live the life of a Christian.
What is the life of a Christian?
To be a Christian is to be content.
That is number one.
The moment you know you are not content, agree with me that you are not a Christian.
Contentment !
Whatever anybody becomes, that will not bother you.
Whether you have little or you don't eat, you will be content.
Whether you have little money or you don't have money to go there and everybody wants to go there,
you will be content.
Contentment is the processing of a Christian.
It is not how much wrong you experience.
When wrong comes, how do you handle the wrong?
As a Christian, when you are wrong, your soul and spirit will be disturbed.
You are not content.
You always count day by day.
Tomorrow, I am so and so here,
I am so and so there, I have not achieved this.
I am schooling.
You are always complaining.
You are not content; you believe you are being cheated.
You believe that there are witches and wizards that are after you.
By your prayer - when you are praying, one can know whether you are a Christian or not.
If I want to know whether this man is a Christian,
if I call him now to pray, through his prayer I will know whether he is a Christian or not.
How do we know Christians? - Through prayer.
A Christian, because he is content, - he may be sick and will say, "Thank You, Jesus!
I glorify Your holy name, I thank You for today!
I will continue to thank You for all what you are about to do and all what you have done!
Thank You!" He will begin to sing, whereas he is sick
because he has left everything for God.
He knows that God knows him more than himself.
But when you are not a Christian, immediately they ask you to pray,
you say, "God, thank You. I'm sick. Heal me!
I'm sick. Heal me!
Please, heal me!
My brother yesterday was healed, and I am better than my brother.
Heal me, Lord!
I have been coming to the church for many years now,
and this man just came today and he was healed.
Lord Jesus, don't leave me. Heal me!
If you don't heal me, I may not come to this church again!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And indeed, he will not come again.
Look at this.
If the processing of this carrot is wrong, when you taste it, you will know
whether it was grown using fertiliser, not natural soil.
Give me the one that is actually grown in natural soil and the one using fertiliser.
When you taste it, you will know the difference.
In fact, the one with the fertiliser affects the health.
The same applies to those chicken, fish you rear, water, everything - processing.
Let someone say, processing.
Processing.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Many of us are here today for the first time and you have forgotten yourself.
When you think back, you will realise that every hour, you must take your drug.
If you don't take your tablet, you will have a fit.
But today, you have been sitting down for the past six hours, and you have forgotten your tablet.
You have just forgotten yourself and nothing has happened to you.
Many of us here - if you were not here, you would have gone to the toilet
up to six to eight times because of diabetes.
But for the past seven hours now, you have been sitting down - no toilet.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Because Jesus has taken more of you and given you more of Him.
What is the meaning of that? It means that you have forgotten yourself.
When you have forgotten yourself, Jesus takes over.
When you leave from here now, by the time you just move outside there, you will start remembering yourself,
"Ah, I have diabetes. I have not taken my drug today".
The moment you remember - urine - you are pressed.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you don't forget yourself, you cannot follow Jesus.
Tell your neighbour: If you don't forget yourself, you cannot follow Jesus.
To forget yourself is to forget your challenges, situation, predicaments or worry.
Remembering yourself and following Jesus is serving two masters.
You are serving two masters.
You follow Jesus and at the same time, you remember your challenges, trouble or worry.
You must forget yourself to follow Jesus.
An example of forgetting yourself is when you sleep.
My brother, when you sleep, your sickness sleeps.
Until when you wake up, you will start feeling the pain.
When you wake up like this, you will start feeling the pain - "Ah, headache!"
But when you were sleeping, you couldn't feel that pain.
This is why scientist decide to give you painkillers.
When they give you this tablet, you will sleep off.
At that moment, there is no pain but when you wake up, the pain will start.
That is an example of forgetting yourself.
In the same vein, when you forget yourself, you have the ability to follow Jesus
because with Jesus, there is no worry, anxiety, challenges, nothing.
No! In Him, there is nothing like that.
That is why when you are following Jesus, challenges are not there.
In Him, in Jesus, there are no challenges or worries.
So it is not possible for you to follow Him with your worry, challenges or situations
because in Him, there is nothing like that.
The SCOAN Sunday Service